Play Xbox One games remotely on any Windows 10 PC
that’s on the same home network.
To get started, connect an Xbox One controller to your PC with a USB cable.
Or, if you’ve purchased an Xbox One Adapter for your controller,
plug it into a USB port on your PC to connect wirelessly.
Plug your USB headset or microphone into the PC,
or your chat headset into your controller, before starting,
if you’re going to use one.
Your headset has to be set as the default playback and recording device in your PC settings.
On your PC, start the Xbox app.
There might be an Xbox One connection option right on the main screen.
If so, click that.
Otherwise, click the Connect icon in the navigation bar on the left.
Your Xbox One shows up in the Add a device list.
Click it to connect.
After you’re connected, select “Stream” to start streaming right away
away and use the controller to move around just like on the Xbox One.
Or, in the Xbox app, start a game streaming by clicking Play from console.
To stop streaming, press the Escape button on the keyboard.
If you’re having trouble connecting to your Xbox, here are some things to check.
Connect your Xbox One and Windows 10 PC to the same network.
Sign into both devices with the same Microsoft account.
On your Xbox One, open the guide and go to All Settings,
Preferences . . . Game DVR and streaming.
Make sure Allow game streaming to other devices is checked.
Go back one level in Settings,
and select SmartGlass connections.
Choose an option that allows SmartGlass connections.
For troubleshooting and performance-improving tips, go to Xbox.com,
and on the Support menu, choose Xbox on Windows 10.
Discover more! Get information and tips from Xbox Help.